Well, just obviously playing against him
when I was at Green Bay um a year ago on
Thanksgiving and I I thought he was
talented. Distributed the ball. He was
kind of like a point guard. Got the ball
out quick, made plays with his feet. Um
had a good two-minute drive, hit Tyreek
for a touchdown late. Um but always been
a fan. He's done a lot of really good
things in this league and um yeah, he
he's had a really good career.
>> Well, I think um you know, Sully and I
have had a lot of really good
conversations about that. um you know
between free agency, the draft and and
the good pieces that we have right now.
You know, the whole goal is to build a
really strong foundation and uh we have
a shared vision for that. It's you know,
I've kind of noted that. It's one of the
reasons that I wanted to come here with
the relationship that I have with him.
Um and in us talking really over the
last two years of of what it will look
like. Um so I think it's exciting and
and that would be the best way that I
can describe it. you know, having a
chance to kind of really build a strong
foundation together with a shared
vision. Um, some could look at it in
certain ways. I look at it is really
exciting.
uh explain that question a little bit
more.
>> I think we'll find out once we start
practice in OTAAS, you know, see I I
think it's fair to say that this roster
is going to look really different after
the draft, right? We have 30 free agents
right now. So, as we go and go through
this process, the roster is going to
look a lot different. So, once we get
through OTAAS, I think I'll have a
better answer for you on that. It's too
hard to tell right now.
>> Uh, well, obviously he was our scout
team quarterback, so you know, a lot of
times he really couldn't do what he does
best because I was sitting there telling
him, you know, if we were playing a drop
back guy and he started scrambling, I'd
tell him, "Hey, you got to stay in the
pocket, man. Like, stop scrambling.
That's not what we're doing today." and
then if we were playing a scrambled he
could kind of play his game and do his
thing. Um, you know, obviously him and I
have a really good relationship and he
always did a really good job and gave us
everything that he had.
>> What's your reflection on?
>> Sure. Um, just really grateful. Um,
obviously we went right from a playoff
game and then I think I had six
interviews in five days. Um, so it was
it was kind of a blur. It was showing up
in my office in Green Bay every day and
you know sitting in Zooms and and
answering a lot of questions, meeting a
lot of really good people um and and
just really learning a lot a lot about
different organizations, how certain
organizations are lined up, what the
structure looks like. And then
ultimately when I came here and I chose
to, you know, really take this in-person
one first, a lot of that had to do with
alignment. You know, I've been a lot of
places and kind of observed what it
looked like with the head coach and the
GM. And I always said to myself, if I
ever get the opportunity to do this in a
perfect world, you want to really be in
alignment with the GM. And in an even
more perfect world, you want to come in
at the same time. Um, so John, Eric, and
I really we share the same vision. Um,
you know, and some people think like we
did this because we're friends. Like I
hate to say we're not friends, but we
kind of are. Um, but we've never hung
out outside the office. I've never been
to his house. We've never went out to
dinner. I think it was a a mutual
working relationship and mutual respect
where we could have honest conversations
where he could tell me something about
what he thought, how we played on
defense, and I could honestly tell him
if I didn't like a prospect, he did. And
I think it just brought us closer
together and that was a huge decision
for me as well as ownership. Um, their
vision, my vision, a joint vision there.
uh they made me feel really comfortable
and I really enjoyed the process and
that's why I chose to take this first
and and ultimately accept the job.
>> What's the key for to year one success
here in Green Bay? What's the key to
making that happen?
>> Well, I think it's going to be more
about the process uh than anything else.
And it's the same thing I would have
said to you in Green Bay when I first
took the job. U building the foundation
the way we want, the play style that we
want, bringing these guys together like
we want. Um, and to me that will be the
first success. And that's going to start
in OTAAS on April 6th. Um, you know, a
lot of guys, it's it's a little
different than Green Bay because a lot
of the guys are here or in Miami because
it's a little warmer than in Green Bay,
so they actually want to stay there in
the offseason. So, I've got a chance to
meet a bunch of these guys already. And
what would be exciting is bringing them
together, going through free agency,
going through the draft and then just
trying to trying to bring them together
and build the culture um of what of what
we want it to be. And I think that will
that will be the beginning to having
some success. And then certainly I mean
look at the end of the day I mean you
you guys know me I'm competitive. I want
to win in everything we do. So I'm not
just going to go in and say it's a
success because we played hard. I mean I
want to win. Um but it will be the start
of the process.
Oh, I think it's it's both, right? I
think there's some really fast players
in college football right now and
there's some great route runners. I just
think it's there's a lot more in the NFL
because it's the best of the best,
right? And there's a lot more route
variety, right, in the different routes,
the different concepts, the different
schemes you're going to get. And it's
just doing it over and over and over
again. And I think in college, you get a
great corner and he shuts a guy down for
a play and you kind of take a deep
breath and relax. If you do that in this
league, you're done. So, it's being able
to do it over and over and over again
and forget about what happened on the
last play.
>> No, unbelievable person. Um, great
friend, highly intelligent, really good
with the players. What he did with
Jordan, um, all the extra time he put in
with him, you could just see that it was
going to happen sooner than later. and
not surprised. Not surprised at all. And
he'll have a really, really bright
future. A guy who played the position,
studied the game. Um, I'll be rooting
for him because he's one of the really
good guys in this league.
>> These Green Bay guys are aggressive. You
guys see that? Sorry. This is after this
we're going to make a shift or you guys
are all going to get me you guys are
going to get me in trouble. So, I'm
sorry. We're going right over here next.
Go.
>> The only thing Jonathan Ganon and I
talked about was whether he was going to
buy my house. And I haven't heard back
from the yet. So, I'm beginning to be a
little bit disappointed in him. Um,
what are you willing to pay for it?
>> I don't have enough.
>> Well, Coach Ganon does. Um, you know, I
think the biggest thing is I talked to
Matt and Goody and kind of gave them
before I left, you know, my feel on all
the players because they asked me to sit
down with them. But if if Genanon does
want to call me up or any of those guys
do, I'll be happy to talk. I mean, you
guys know I love those players. Um, and
I love Matt. So, whatever I can do in
the little time that I have, I'll I'll
be happy to help them.
Eric, that regards
>> just constant conversation and and I
kind of answered that about success
already. Um, just constant conversation,
communication, making sure him and I are
on the same page. Um,
you know, and I think, you know, there's
a lot of roster questions right now and
and and and we've got work to do.
>> How do I evaluate them and edge rushers?
Yeah, I mean the the edge rusher
position right now um you know we need
to fill those we need to fill that room
up. There's there's not many left on the
roster right now. So not many to
evaluate. So we have to obviously add
some depth there. But there's some good
pieces in place that I'm really excited
to to work with. Um and the same with
the quarterbacks. You know there's
there's some guys that have played
football. Um there's some youth there
obviously. So excited to have those guys
compete as well.
I like them all. I just I think having
variation is so important. I mean, you
might say we're going to be a 4-3
defense, which we'll base out a 4-3, but
I'd like to get in the 4-3 structures
and 3 four structures all out of the
same personnel grouping. So, I'm not
subbing and you're saying, "Oh, now he's
in 34, subbing back, now they're in
4-3." I think front variation is huge
and having the ability to be multiple.
At the same time, I think it's really
important to find out who we end up with
on this roster and figure out what we do
best. Um, and then it will be my job to
put to put that scheme in place. I have
a lot of good ideas. Uh, but at the same
time, even if you look back to my past
and in my first year back in the NFL, we
played a ton of three, four variations
with four down and we had different guys
in the inside and then when we made a
trade last year, I had to kind of flip
it and then we had some injuries, so I
had to flip back. So, at the end of the
day, we'll do whatever we can to to make
sure we're playing good defense.
>> Why do you think Larry Johnson has so
consistently been able to produce
>> at Ohio State? I just my my one year
with Larry just just a really good
technical coach, really demanding with
his players, builds great relationships,
and he's a great evaluator. I mean, he's
recruited some really really good
talent. Um, I mean, even when I was
there, there were some great players and
there will continue to be and and Ryan
does such a great job with the
evaluation process and then building
those guys from the ground up. Um,
Larry's a great coach.
Yes, absolutely. Um, and that that
actually I've been thinking about a lot
lately. Um, the question was about San
Francisco and seeing the alignment
there. When I got there, it was Kyle's
first year. It was obviously John was a
new GM and Kyle and they were coming in
together. Um, and I thought that
alignment was really strong. And now
what people forget we started off 0 and9
but they built it the right way and they
built a really strong foundation and it
just slowly the improvement where then
three years later they went to the Super
Bowl. But just watching them all work
together whether it was in football
meetings or whether it was the draft
process.
two phenomenal human beings who are
really good at what they do, who are
lined up together, who weren't afraid to
have hard conversations and disagree,
but at the end of the day had each
other's back and and that's I think one
of the huge reasons why they've had
success. But 100% yes.
>> Hold on. Can I get someone else just
because I I want to kind of be fair.
>> Yeah, Bobby and I were together in uh
San Francisco. Bobby was a defensive
quality control coach with me. Um and
and we spent a lot of time together.
Highly intelligent, really knows
football, both sides of the ball. You
know the story. Kyle took him on offense
and trained him with the pedigree to run
his system. Had success in Houston. Him
and I kept in touch, interviewed a bunch
of guys and and Bobby hit a home run. I
trust him as a person, which is huge for
me as a developer because as we build
this foundation, we're going to have to
develop players. Like I think that's the
thing that people forget. This is about
developing whoever we come out of this
draft with, right? I think he's
unbelievable with that and I love his
scheme.
>> Yeah, he's went through it just just
like in anything else. You go through
something and you learn from your
mistakes or you learn from your
successes. And I think, you know, people
might point out how it ended with Bobby,
but look at the success that he had,
too. Look at what he did with the
quarterback in his first year. I believe
he's rookie of the year. Look at what he
did in the playoffs. Um, and personally,
I had to coach against him, so I know
exactly what that was like, too. And
then over the last year, you know, being
back in Miami, picking up some new ideas
and just going through his thoughts and
you can see the growth he's had from
that time, which excites me.
>> Say, say that again. plan to address
glaring needs on the offensive line.
>> Yeah, I think those are like all our
needs right now. Again, anytime you have
30 free agents, I mean, there's going to
be there's going to be needs across the
board. It's get the best players we can
with the right mindset who are great
people and then we got to develop them
and coach them. I mean, that's just
going to be the key to this whole entire
thing, which kind of excites me.
Well, you got to have the physical tools
cuz I mean I have the football IQ to do
it, but there's no way I could ever
play, right? So, you got to have and I'm
joking. Well, no, I really don't have
the I'm kind of not joking, but um you
have to have the physical tools to have
the ability to play, right? Then to play
multiple positions is hard. I mean, even
what we asked some guys to do in Green
Bay to move around as I watch the tape,
there's times when we might have
overdone that a little bit and then
there's other guys who no problem. So,
you do need the football IQ, especially
if you're going to ask somebody to do it
early in their career. It's probably
easier to do it later as they get older
and they have more experience at one
position. But, you don't want to take
somebody early and spread them too thin
because then they're not going to be
good at anything.
Um, I think I think it depends on the
individual to be honest with you. Um,
just in my experience, I could tell you
one position, but then I started to
think about it and a guy came in and was
able to do it. I just think it all
depends on the individual.
>> I think you stay level-headed win or
lose. I mean, that's I think that's
probably the biggest thing that I take
pride in. Whether we won a game, whether
we lost a game, shame on me if I didn't
come in the same exact way. Because if
you believe in the process and you
believe in everything that you're doing
and you believe in the players you have
and you believe in the coaches you have,
then you got to just stick with it no
matter the situation. Cuz the moment I
start to go one way or the other or
waiver or change, everyone else is going
to do the same thing. And that can't
happen. So sadly, I've been in those
situations and I'd be able to hold the
room together. I hope not to be in that
situation again, but I think it's
prepared me for wins and losses to be
the same guy and and to stick with the
people you believe in, the process that
you believe in. speak
with Kevin obviously
took a lot of obvious
>> yeah I mean I when I interviewed him I
was blown away the knowledge that he has
the football experience that he has what
he did for that entire organization.
Don't forget he won a Super Bowl and
behind the scenes what he did with that
offense and with that whole team and
listening to him talk and his football
knowledge and not just about offense but
about game management about situational
football. I I got off to Zoom and I said
to Bobby, I said, "We got to try to hire
this guy." And he had other
opportunities and other options. Um I
think he's going to be a huge asset to
what we do. And I think often it's
unfair to judge anybody off of one
single year.
>> Example of that. You say, "Oh, details."
>> Yeah, I we we'll keep those as examples
for right now. To me,
for an edge.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, certain edge guys
when you watch the film, it's it starts
to me with the ability to rush the
passer, right? And then can they play
the run? And then what you do, you look
at if some of them are bigger, for
example, you get a 275 edge rusher that
maybe is more of a speed to power guy.
Can he go inside and kick in and beat a
guard with his quickness? Right? Maybe
he's not a speed rusher on the outside,
but maybe you get him into a passing
situation. You can kick him down on the
inside. And then it's the same thing for
an off-the-ball backer. When you look at
an off-the-ball backer, how does he play
in space? How does he react to the run,
but then is he a guy that you can match
up one-on-one with the backs and run
through backs and becomes a good
blitzer? So, when you I think people
make mistakes. They just watch like
point of attack film. I think you got to
sit back and really watch game tape to
see all the different things that
they're asked to do.
short arms, long arms are concern
>> with some guys it is. Some guys with
short arms, I mean, they just they kind
of get eaten up, but some guys are so
quick where they can get their hands
inside first and still disengage. So, in
an ideal world, would you love to have a
guy with long arms? Yeah, absolutely.
But I think there's other guys that have
short arms and that are really good edge
rushers or really good inside. But it is
definitely a conversation at all
positions. It's the same thing with a
5'9 corner. If you have a 5'9 corner
with 33 inch arms and all of a sudden
he's beat but he can reach it makes him
a lot taller than he is if he's a 5'9
quarter with 28 in arms, right? If you
get a 61 corner with short arms, the
analytics of it, it kind of all adds up.
But good question.
>> Yeah, I think you can't look at that as
being black and white. There's some
games where we didn't close and there's
other games where we closed with an
interception in the end zone or a fourth
and one stop. So, I think you got to
look game by game and try to figure out
why you didn't. You know, was it scheme?
Was it putting the players in in good
positions, bad positions? I think just
like anything else, when we study our
tape, and right now what we're doing is
we're studying the two years at Green
Bay, the film, it's what did we do well
over the two years, what didn't we do
well? And some of those situations we
didn't do well. Some of those situations
we're in position to make a play and we
didn't make the play. Some of the
situations I should have made a better
call, right? So, you kind of got to look
at everything and you got to get better
in everything that you do. But win or
lose, you got to figure that out on the
tape. It ain't just about when you don't
make the play at the end of the game.
>> Last question.
Yeah, I think anytime you can get an
eval of a player live and you're really
down there and you see it, you know,
whether it's a DB, for example, and you
can see his foot speed, you can see his
ability to break and drive. But then I
also think sometimes it's bigger than
that. It's a guy jumping out first in
the drill. Is the guy like got a little
bit of edge to him? Is he standing
straight up? Is he paying attention? Is
he cheering the other guys on? Like
what's his makeup all about? So
sometimes you can't see that on the
tape, but you can see it when you
observe a guy and you can kind of get a
feel for what he's all about. What type
of energy does he have? Does he have any
leadership ability? Right? I think
that's kind of what people miss when
they say, "I'm not going to come out and
watch any of this stuff. I'm just going
to watch it on tape." Because you can't
tell that on the tape. So, there's
nothing better than a live evaluation.